# M. Adil Mushtaq

# **Electronics Engineer**

House no. 40 E-Market PECHS Block 06, Karachi adilmagsiii@gmail.com
0340-3062954

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE:**

Electronics Engineer having PEC number, pursing a technical and management level position in a prominent organization in order to build a long term career by capitalizing the best of my technical knowledge & educational, to serve the firm with an exceptional output and to excel among the professionals, where I can exploit my expertise with resilient commitment and perseverance for the progressive evolution of the corporation.

## **EXPERIENCE:**

1. MCR ENGINEER

KTN Entertainment Channel

March 2017 to July 2017

## Job Responsibilities:

Master Control Room, the technical heart of a broadcast operation, where the signals from both audio and video passes over preceding to transmission.

- Worked at different video monitors, satellite receivers, video tape machines and transmission equipment.
- · Responsible for incoming and outgoing broadcast lines.
- Responsible for incoming feeds for the use of studio operations.
- Ensure technical standards are maintained across the operation.
- Responsible for checking the quality of content.
- Make sure the transmission meets government regulations (station ID, indecency, watershed rules ETC) and respond to any technical issues (over-modulation and "dead air") from other areas of the operation.

# 2. Design Engineer

Creative Dynamics Engineering

October 2017 - Present

Currently working at Creative Dynamics Engineering as a Design Engineer.

INTERNEE:

Pakistan Aeronautical Complex Kamra (Minhas Air Base)

Dec 16 to Jan 17

INTERNEE:

Pakistan International Airline

June to July 2016

INTERNEE:

Pakistan Telecommunication Company Limited

June-July 2014

## **EDUCATION:**

Degree	Institute	year
BE Electronics	PAF- Karachi Institute Of Economics & Technology	2016-Dec
Intermediate	Aisha Bawany Govt: College	2012
Matriculation	Brooks Grammar School	2010

### **EXTRACURRICULARULAM**

# ADVANCED ENGLISH LEARNING COURSE

# **Domino English Learning Center**

August-October 2017

Three months advanced English learning course where I learned advanced level English, moreover I participated in several competitions hold in the premises of domino for improving English fluency, enhancing self-confidence, preparing for jobs interviews and boosting up interpersonal skills.

- Got 1st position in inter campuses English debate
- Got 1<sup>st</sup> position in inter campuses SCRABLE GAME
- Got A1 grade at overall performance in three months

AUTOCAD (Electrical & Civil)

Al-Ghous Polytechnic Institute

March - June 2014

#### **FINAL YEAR PROJECT:**

Optical Eavesdropping System.

My Final Year Project approved for funding by National ICT R&D Fund Ministry of Information &Technology under National Grassroots ICT Research Initiative (2015-16).

#### **TERM REPORTS & PROJECTS:**

- Line Following & Obstacle Avoidance Robot
- Proportional Integrator Differential (PID) Controller For DC Motor
- 32 Volts Variable Power Supply
- Automatic Cubes Packaging System Through Delta PLC & HMI
- Automatic light Sensing Lamp
- DC Motor Speed Controlled & Feedback System Using PIC Controller
- Temperature Sensor using Ardiuno

# **KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES:**

- Punctual
- Smart worker
- Deadline Oriented

- Dedicated
- Determinate
- Creative Mind

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS:**

- WPL Soft
- PLC & HMI
- MATLAB
- Protieus
- Multisim
- CVAVR

- Orcade
- Solid Work
- AutoCad
- MS Office
- Cisco Packet
- C++

# **HOBBIES & INTEREST**

- WEB SURFING
- CRICKET
- READING
- MUSIC

- SOCIAL MEDIA
- MOVIES
- LITRATURE
- HISTROY

### **REFERENCES**

· Will be furnished on request